A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Peace and Social Justice Program (PSJ), Governance and Civil Society, Senior Program Officer, Office Files of Michael Lipsky FA725
Rockefeller Archive Center
Ford Foundation records, Peace and Social Justice Program (PSJ), Governance and Civil Society, Senior Program Officer, Office Files of Michael Lipsky
1991-2003
Rockefeller Archive Center
Lipsky, Michael
Ford Foundation
FA725
18 Cubic Feet
Conditions Governing Access
Records more than 10 years old are open for research with select materials restricted as noted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC.
Appraisal
Box 43136 has not been deposited at, or otherwise transferred to, RAC.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Ford Foundation archive was deposited at RAC in 2011. Ford Foundation records, correspondence, reports, program files and officers papers were transferred to, and accessioned by, RAC beginning in 2011. Accessions continue as necessary.
Arrangement
As received.
Scope and Contents
Correspondence, reports, state, city and project files.
- Side File: India (Box 43107)
- Side File: Budgeting - Nigeria (Box 43107)
- Side File: China (Box 43107)
- Side File: South Africa (Box 43107)
- Impumelelo: Innovations Awards Programme (Box 43107)
- Philippines (Box 43107)
- Side File: Uganda (Box 43107)
- South Africa Report (Box 43107)
- Mexico File (Box 43107)
- Eastern Europe (Box 43111)
- East Africa Ml-Country (Box 43111)
- East Africa Conference (Box 43111)
- Columbia (Box 43111)
- Code Sria (Box 43111)
- India (Box 43111)
- Workshop on Local Practice (Box 43124)
- Arkansas Advocates for Children & Family (Box 43124)
- Colorado Center on Law and Policy (Box 43124)
- Indiana Coalition on Housing and Homeless Issues (Box 43124)
- Voices for Connecticut's Children (Box 43124)
- Citizens for Missouri's Children (Box 43124)
- Kentucky Youth Advocates (Box 43124)
- Kansas Action for Children (Box 43124)
- Association of Children of NJ (Box 43124)
- Children's Defense Fund - Ohio (Box 43124)
- SFAI "General" File (Box 43124)
  Separated Materials
  Files removed in February, 2004 by Urvashi Vaid, Deputy Director, Governance and Civil Society, Peace and Social Justice Program, for ongoing program activities.
- Draft Application Package for SFAI Operational Grants (Box 43124)
- SFAI "basis" File (Box 43124)
- Delta Project - Side File (Box 43125)
- Tennessee (Box 43125)
- Alabama (Box 43125)
- Colorado (Box 43125)
- Idaho (Box 43125)
- Kentucky (Box 43125)
- Oregon (Box 43125)
- Oregon Trip 8/1 (Box 43125)
- Washington (Box 43125)
- Minnesota (Box 43125)
- Nevada (Box 43125)
- North Carolina (Box 43125)
- USA (South) (Box 43125)
- Texas (Box 43125)
- Colorado 2003 (Box 43125)
- OMG - Side File (Box 43125)
- Children's Action Alliance (Box 43126)
- Michigan League for Human Services (Box 43126)
- Voices for Illinois (Box 43126)
- Alabama Arise (Box 43126)
- Maine Center for Economic Policy (Box 43126)
- North Carolina Justice (Box 43126)
- Idaho (Box 43126)
- Oregon Center for Public Policy (Box 43126)
- Team Education Fund (Box 43126)
- SFAI - Responses to 9/11 (Box 43126)
- Arkansas Advocates for Children (Box 43126)
- New Jersey (Box 43126)
- Wisconsin Council (Box 43126)
- Colorado (Box 43126)
- Kentucky Youth (Box 43126)
- Fiscal Policy Center (Box 43126)
- State Fiscal Analysis- Initiative Renewals (Box 43126)
- SFAI- Related Documents (Box 43126)
- Film Project - Innovation 10th Anniversary (Box 43127)
- Ambrica Productions (Box 43127)
- Blackside (Box 43127)
- Dick Young Productions, Ltd. (Box 43127)
- Fire Thorn productions (Box 43127)
- Gail Pellett Productions (Box 43127)
- Hedrick Smith Productions, Inc. (Box 43127)
- Midnight Films (Box 43127)
- Northern Light Productions (Box 43127)
- Innovations 1995: Thomas & Milliken Speeches (Box 43127)
- Innovations 1995: Invitation List (Box 43127)
- Innovations 1995 RGA (Winners & Finalists) (Box 43127)
- Innovations Awards Letters (Box 43127)
- 1995 - City of Tampa Hillsboro County Health Care Plan (Box 43127)
- 1995 - City of Boulder Genesis: Healthy Young Families (Box 43127)
- 1995 - City of Albany Center for Technology in Government (Box 43127)
- 1995 - City of Indianapolis Competition and Costing (Box 43127)
- 1995 - City of San Antonio Project Quest (Box 43127)
- 1995 - City of Boston Elder Choice (Box 43127)
- 1995 - City of NY Civil Enforcement Initiative (Box 43127)
- 1995 - City of Louisville City Work (Box 43127)
- 1995 - City of Shreveport Hamilton Terrace Learning Center (Box 43127)
- 1995 - City of Seattle Catalist (Box 43127)
- 1995 - City of Madison Recruiting the Best and the Brightest (Box 43127)
- 1995 - Salt Lake City Utah Arts Endowment Fund (Box 43127)
- 1995 - City of Honolulu Hawaii FYI (Box 43127)
- 1995 - City of Apple Valley The Ramp Project (Box 43127)
- 1995 - City of Sacramento California Foodlink (Box 43127)
- 1995 - City of Mineola Recidivist Alcohol Probationer (Box 43127)
- 1995 - City of NY Red Light Camera Program (Box 43127)
- 1995 - City of Austin - Volunteer Interpreter Service (Box 43127)
- Innovations 95 - Proposal Guidelines/Small Grants (Box 43127)
- Innovations 95 Proposal Guidelines/ Large Grants (Box 43127)
- Innovations 95 - Current/Rutledge Guidelines (Box 43127)
- Innovations 95 - Press Releases (Box 43127)
- Innovations Post - Event Press Clippings 95 (Box 43127)
- Innovations 95 – National Selection Committee Names & Addresses (Box 43127)
- National Selection Committee List (Box 43127)
- Innovations 95 - Lipsky's Letters to Federal Winners (8/30) (Box 43127)
- Innovations 95 - F. Thomas Letters to Federal Winners (8/18) (Box 43127)
- Innovations 95 Committee Member (Box 43127)
- Innovations 95 - Committee Members' Reminder Letter (Box 43127)
- Innovation 95 - Winners Schedule of the Day Letter (Box 43127)
- Design Copy and text for 1995 Innovations brochure (Box 43127)
- Letters to new National Selection Committee Members (Box 43127)
- Letters to new old National Selection Committee Members (Box 43127)
- Innovations (Box 43127)
- Innovations 95 - Frank Thomas letter (Box 43127)
- F. Thomas letter to VP Gore (Box 43127)
- Innovations 95- Letters to Finalists (July) (Box 43127)
- Innovations 95 - Letters to Award Winners (July) (Box 43127)
- Harvard University Innovation 95 (Box 43127)
- Innovations 95 Correspondence from M. Booth & Assoc. (Box 43127)
- India (Box 43128)
- Israel (Box 43128)
- Kenya (Box 43128)
- Latin America (Box 43128)
- Latin America (Governance) (Box 43128)
- Decentralized Governance in Asia (Box 43128)
- China Trip - Sept. 4th-12th 2000 (Box 43128)
- Brazil (Box 43128)
- Brazil Innovations Program (Box 43128)
- Australia (Box 43128)
- Bangladesh (Box 43128)
- Brazil and Brazil Notes (Box 43128)
- South Africa (Box 43128)
- Fiscal Policy Inst. (Box 43129)
- Children's Action Alliance (Box 43129)
- State Fiscal Analysis Initiative (Box 43129)
- Logo Memo (Box 43129)
- Washington State (Box 43129)
- Workplan-Washington Living Wage Movement (Box 43129)
- Innovations Scrapbook (Box 43129)
- ML's POM 6/19/99 (Box 43129)
- Seminars - E Government (Box 43129)
- Montana (Box 43129)
- Minnesota Nonprofit Association (Box 43129)
- Nevada (Box 43129)
- North Carolina Justice and Comm. Dev. Ctr. (Box 43129)
- South Carolina (Box 43129)
- Voices for Illinois Children (Box 43129)
- US State Memo (Box 43129)
- Idaho (Box 43129)
- Harvard Project - Native American (Box 43129)
- Contacts Lists (Box 43129)
- SFAI Desk File (Box 43129)
- SFAI Proposals (Box 43129)
- Michigan League SFAI FY2000 Prop. (Box 43129)
- Filing (Box 43129)
- SFAI 1998 Renewal (Box 43129)
- President's Summit 4/27 - 29 (Box 43129)
- SFAI Guidance for Spring Site Visits (Box 43129)
- Spring 1994 Site Visits Reports (SFAI) (Box 43129)
- Classification of Lobbying Rules for SFAI Grantees (Box 43129)
- SFAI Meetings (Box 43129)
- State Fiscal Analysis Initiative Inquiries (Box 43129)
- SFAI Texas Foundation Mailing & Responses (Box 43129)
- SFAI Mailing & Responses (Box 43129)
- SFAI Consultant/Kay Sherwood (Box 43129)
- State Fiscal Analysis RGA (Box 43129)
- Innovations 1999 (Box 43136)
- MALDEF (Box 43138)
- Institute on Innovation (Box 43138)
- Ralph Lysyshy 10/25/00 (Box 43138)
- National Whistleblower Center (Box 43138)
- Documentation - Amy Nogle (Box 43138)
- FedEx (Box 43138)
- Galing Pook Assessment (Box 43138)
- Grant Files for IR (Box 43138)
- Portland Fund for Civic Innovation (Box 43138)
- Hold for telephone call back (Box 43138)
- E-mail and Faxes awaiting Response-Karen's desk (Box 43138)
- Portland State University (Box 43138)
- Active File (Box 43138)
- London WWP Meeting (Box 43138)
- Judith Tendler (Box 43138)
- Indiana Univ. - Lee Hamilton 3/99 (Box 43138)
- Report and Roundtable Discussion on American Democracy - prepared for the Joyce Foundation (1989-90) (Box 43138)
- ML - Program Officer Memo - Biographic Summary of M. Lipsky (Box 43139)
- April (Box 43139)
- Miscellaneous (Box 43139)
- Media Coverage for Innovations Program (Box 43139)
- Center for Policy Alternatives - Junes 16, 2001 (Box 43139)
- ML - Program Officer Memo - Biographic Summary of M. Lipsky (Box 43139)
- April (Box 43139)
- Miscellaneous (Box 43139)
- Media Coverage for Innovations Program (Box 43139)
- Center for Policy Alternatives - Junes 16, 2001 (Box 43139)
- Council for Excellence in Government - Proposal 10/2001 (Box 43139)
- Collaborations that Count (Box 43139)
- Trustee PSJ Committee (Box 43139)
- Int'l Civil Society - Budget Work Support Project - April 29-30, 2002 (Box 43139)
- Nat'l Civic League (Box 43139)
- Leadership for a Changing World Awards Celebration (Box 43139)
- Meeting w/Bill Rowe & Kim Carton (Box 43139)
- Bob Fulkerson - Progressive Leadership of NV (Box 43139)
- Economic & Social Policy Discussion Panels (Box 43139)
- LCW - Partnership Meeting (Box 43139)
- Monthly Meetings with Mike & Urvashi (Box 43139)
- Partnership Launch 10/97+ (Box 43140)
- Introduction to GIST (Box 43140)
- Innovations 1994-to be filed (Box 43140)
- Innovations 1995: application (Box 43140)
- Innovations 1995: Jane Dunne Report (Box 43140)
- Innovations replication 1996 (Box 43140)
- Strategic alliances Innovations 1996 (Box 43140)
- Update on Innovations 1996 (Box 43140)
- Harvard University (Box 43140)
- Innovations News - Dec 3rd and after (Box 43140)
- Commission on Civil Society (Box 43140)
- Berkeley, California /Grantmakers (Box 43140)
- Pennsylvania Partnership for Children (Box 43140)
- Wisconsin council on children and Families (Box 43140)
- Parade Magazine - Communications Initiative (Box 43140)
- American Perspectives - Communications Initiative (Box 43140)
- Communications Updates (M&G) - Communications Initiative (Box 43140)
- AFL/CIO - Communications Initiative (Box 43140)
- Restoring the balance (Martin/Glantz) - Communications Initiative (Box 43140)
- American Association of Museums - Communications Initiative (Box 43140)
- American Medical Association - Communications Initiative (Box 43140)
- American Youth Museum - Communications Initiative (Box 43140)
- Catholic Charities - Communications Initiative (Box 43140)
- Edison International - Communications Initiative (Box 43140)
- Geico - Communications Initiative (Box 43140)
- Rhode Island KIDS count (Box 43140)
- United vision for Idaho (Box 43140)
- Voices for children in Nebraska (Box 43140)
- Oregon Center for Public Policy (Box 43140)
- National Council of Nonprofit Assoc. - Pending Grant Action (Box 43141)
- Tennessee (Box 43141)
- China (Box 43141)
- New Leaders Proposals (Box 43141)
- SFAI Announcements/Press Releases/Responses to Inquiries (Box 43141)
- History of SFAI (Box 43141)
- State Fiscal Analysis Project - Consultants (Box 43141)
- SFAI - 6/94 Marilinas (Box 43141)
- Maryland/Attachments Mano/Grant Application of SFAI (Box 43141)
- Good Housekeeping (Box 43142)
- Museum of Television and Radio (Box 43142)
- TV Content Analysis Project (Box 43142)
- Minnesota (Box 43142)
- Meeting with Pat McGinnis, Gleason 5/23 (Box 43142)
- Michigan Community Service Meeting 5/16 -17 (Box 43142)
- Why has confidence in Government declined? 5/9 - 10 (Box 43142)
- Carolyn Lukensmeyer Meeting 4/1 (Box 43142)
- Ester Fuchs/Phil Thompson Meeting 4/11 (Box 43142)
- Local Governance Grantee Meeting 6/12 - 6/15 (Box 43142)
- Past Trips - Michael Lipsky 1996 (Box 43142)
- Florence Bonner (Box 43142)
- Gregg Petersmeyer (Box 43142)
- Medical Care for Children Partnership Advisory Council Retreat - Oct 26 "Gleason" Meeting (Box 43142)
- Lizzy Flanagan/Youth on Board (Box 43142)
- Design Cities Action Clinic (Box 43142)
- Dinner at Fall Conference for Comm. Fds (Box 43142)
- APSA Meeting (Box 43142)
- GIST Summer Meeting (Box 43142)
- Governance BM Meeting (Box 43142)
- Hilton Foundation (Box 43142)
- 20th Century Fund (Box 43142)
- Kettering Foundation (Box 43142)
- Ford Positive Business Climates (Box 43142)
- Council on Foundations (Box 43142)
- National Youth Service Day (Box 43142)
- Curriculum Response to the Changing Policy Landscape - Sheraton City Hotel (Box 43142)
- Joint Center Annual Dinner (Box 43142)
- Washington DC Jan. 18-19, 1996. Comm. on State & Local Public Service Mtg. on State (Box 43142)
- Capacity & Devolution (Box 43142)
- State Fiscal Analysis Initiative Newsletter (Box 43142)
- Key Contacts for Kids Count (Box 43142)
- Thank you letters to Consultants (Box 43142)
- Annie E. Casey Foundation (Box 43142)
- Charles Stewart Mott Foundation (Box 43142)
- Other Foundation Partners (Box 43142)
- Reactions to State Fiscal Project (Box 43142)
- IBM Corp - Ken Thornton (Box 43142)
- League of Women Voters (Box 43142)
- MTV Networks - Helen Boehm (Box 43142)
- National Cable Television Assoc. - Decker Anstrom (Box 43142)
- National Audubon Society - John Flicker (Box 43142)
- National Council of Churches of Christ - Rich Killmer/Eileen Lindner (Box 43142)
- National Resources Defense Council - John Adams/Frances Beinecke (Box 43142)
- Scholastic (Box 43142)
- NAM/Tenneco - Art House (Box 43142)
- Union of American Hebrew Congregations - Leonard Fein (Box 43142)
- United Negro College Fund - Alan Kirschner (Box 43142)
- Urban League - Hugh Price (Box 43142)
- World Wildlife Fund - Katherine Fuller (Box 43142)
- YWCA of the USA - Jo Uehara (Box 43142)
- China: Side File (Box 43143)
- Philippines: Side File (Box 43143)
- Nigeria: Side File (Box 43143)
- Brazil: Side File (Box 43143)
- Chile: Side File (Box 43143)
- Collaborations that Count (CTC) Side File (Box 43143)
- State Strategies Fund (Box 43143)
- Homeland Security Side File (Box 43143)
- TANF Reauthorization Side File (Box 43143)
- Harvard Desk File (Box 43143)
- Role of the State Desk File (Box 43143)
- Mike Edwards Desk File (Box 43143)
- B/Fan Desk File (Box 43143)
- ML Desk File/CBPP International Project (Box 43143)
- SFAI Desk File (Box 43143)
- International Budget Project, 2012:064:001 (Box 43143)
- Miles Rapoport Report/PVC (Box 43143)
- PGA (Box 43143)
- PGA – Honoring Nations 2003 (Box 43143)
- CPA – PGA (Box 43143)
- Rapoport – Forum of Democracy and Trade (Box 43143)
- Copies for Miles (Box 43143)
- Draft Report (Box 43143)
- Idaho Fund (Box 43143)
- Memos to Void (Box 43143)
- Materials sent to Tom Burne (Box 43143)
- San Francisco Breakfast (Box 43143)
- CBPP Funding State Con 12/7-12/10 (Box 43143)
- PUC – Forum on Democracy and Trade (Box 43143)
- National Constitution Center (Box 43143)
- PUC Isaac Shapiro (Box 43143)
- PUC Transparency International (Box 43143)
- PUC Africa Budget Project (Box 43143)
- PUC – Center for Economic and Policy Research (Box 43143)
- PUC – 5/02 Harrison Inst. (Box 43143)
- SFAI Assets Grants (Box 43143)
- PUC – Kennedy School (Box 43143)
- Susan Stroud – National Service (Box 43143)
- Worker Retention Ordinance (Box 43143)
- LAANE California Project (Box 43143)
- PUC David Gergan (Box 43143)
- Center for Government Studies (Box 43143)
- PUC – Transparency International (Box 43143)
- PUC – Government Accountability (Box 43143)
- Study of National Intermediaries (Box 43143)
- Partnership for Public Service (Box 43143)
- PUC Tom Burns (Box 43143)
- Washington Association of Churches and Chris Haugen (Box 43143)
- Women's Funding Movement Report, 1991 (Box 43308)
- Issues and Media in the Presidential Elections, 1991-1992 (Box 43308)
- Latino Policy Centers, 1993 (Box 43308)
- John Koprowski, 1992 (Box 43308)
- Partnership For Trust in Government, ML-Sub, 1997 (Box 43308)
- State Fiscal Analysis Initiative (SFAI), ML-Sub, 1997 (Box 43308)
- Public Employees, 1992 (Box 43308)
- Grantmakers' Income Security Taskforce (GIST), 1993-1994 (Box 43308)
- GIST meeting of July 20, 1992, 1992 July 20 (Box 43308)
- David Arnold memos, 1991-1992 (Box 43308)
- Campaign Finance, 1992 (Box 43308)
- Texas Conference – ML (Michael Lipsky) Texas Grantees, 1997 June 10 (Box 43308)
- Texas Conference (for Texas grantees). ML Working Files, 1997 (Box 43308)
- Youth Service/Trustees Meeting, 1994 (Box 43308)
- Changing Domestic Priorities II, 1993-1994 (Box 43308)
- Improving Governance in U.S. – Overview of goals and objectives, 1991-1992 (Box 43308)
- Final Application Package for SFAI Operational Grants, 1994 (Box 43308)
- Bob Greenstein, Executive Director of Center on Budget and Policy Priorities (Box 43308)
- Judith Tendler paper, 1997 (Box 43308)
- Consultant: Tobi Walker, 2000 (Box 43308)
- Political Participation Meeting, 1989 (Box 43308)
- AF: Local Democracy Project, 1992-1993 (Box 43308)
- National Service, 1997 October (Box 43308)
- Correspondence and notes, 1965 (Box 43308)